James B. Olcott Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
James B. Olcott Papers.
undated, 1883-1916.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Olcott, James B.
1.75 linear feet.
James B. Olcott was a member of the first Board of Trustees of Storrs Agricultural School, now the University of Connecticut.
MSS19770003
Biography
James B. Olcott lived in Manchester, Connecticut. He was appointed to a committee of three to investigate and report on an offer of land and money from Augustus and Charles Storrs to establish a school of agriculture in Storrs, Connecticut. The report from the committee was favorable, and the 1880 offer was accepted in 1881 by the General Assembly, and the Storrs Agricultural School was established. The organization of the school was entrusted to T.S. Gold, J.B. Olcott, and S.W. Johnson. James B. Olcott was a member of the first Board of Trustees of Storrs Agricultural School.
Scope and Content
The majority of the collection consists of correspondence from Olcott to "Miss Tudor". A small numbers of items are addressed to Mr. Olcott or are from Emily Olcott. Some agricultural publications are included.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of records pertaining to the University's history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.
Occupations:
Civic leader.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated in 1977 by Mrs. Harry A. Nichols.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1883-1916
  - undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 1883-1885 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 1886 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1886 January (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 1886 February (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1886 March (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1886 April (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1886 May (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1886 June (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 1886 July (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - 1886 August (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - 1886 September (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - 1886 October (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - 1886 November (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - 1886 December (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - 1887 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - 1887 January (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - 1887 February (Box 2:, Folder 18)
  - 1887 March (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - 1887 April (Box 2:, Folder 20)
  - 1887 May (Box 2:, Folder 21)
  - 1887 June (Box 2:, Folder 22)
  - 1887 July (Box 2:, Folder 23)
  - 1887 August (Box 2:, Folder 24)
  - 1887 September (Box 2:, Folder 25)
  - 1887 October (Box 2:, Folder 26)
  - 1887 November (Box 2:, Folder 27)
  - 1887 December (Box 2:, Folder 28)
  - 1888 February (Box 2:, Folder 29)
  - 1888 March (Box 2:, Folder 30)
  - 1888 April (Box 2:, Folder 31)
  - 1888 May (Box 2:, Folder 32)
  - 1888 June (Box 2:, Folder 33)
  - 1888 July (Box 2:, Folder 34)
  - 1888 August (Box 2:, Folder 35)
  - 1888 September (Box 2:, Folder 36)
  - 1888 October (Box 2:, Folder 37)
  - 1888 November (Box 3:, Folder 38)
  - 1888 December (Box 3:, Folder 39)
  - 1889 January (Box 3:, Folder 40)
  - 1889 February (Box 3:, Folder 41)
  - 1889 March (Box 3:, Folder 42)
  - 1889 April (Box 3:, Folder 43)
  - 1889 May (Box 3:, Folder 44)
  - 1889 June (Box 3:, Folder 45)
  - 1889 July (Box 3:, Folder 46)
  - 1889 August (Box 3:, Folder 47)
  - 1889 September (Box 3:, Folder 48)
  - 1890 September (Box 3:, Folder 49)
  - 1890 October (Box 3:, Folder 50)
  - 1890 November (Box 3:, Folder 51)
  - 1890 December (Box 3:, Folder 52)
  - 1891 January (Box 3:, Folder 53)
  - 1891 February (Box 3:, Folder 54)
  - 1891 March (Box 4:, Folder 55)
  - 1891 October - December (Box 4:, Folder 56)
  - 1892 January - April (Box 4:, Folder 57)
  - 1892 July (Box 4:, Folder 58)
  - 1897 December (Box 4:, Folder 59)
  - Publications, undated, 1886-1916 (Box 4:, Folder 60)